Guide to the Jeffery Collection of Diamond Promotional Materials, 1939-1998, bulk 1974-1998 RL.00633
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jeffery Collection of Diamond Promotional Materials
1939-1998, bulk 1974-1998
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jeffery, Robert K.
RL.00633
4.5 Linear Feet
about 459 items
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Jeffery Collection of Diamond Promotional Materials was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2000.
Biographical Note
Jeffery is a longtime administrator and lecturer in retail sales, administration, and the manufacturing of jewelry.
Collection Overview
Collection documents the artwork and printed promotional materials Robert K. Jeffery commissioned, used, or referenced in diamond advertising. Most items are the output of the advertising agency N. W. Ayer and Son, Inc., often featuring De Beers diamonds and outdoor advertising promotions. Other items are more general to the diamond marketing industry, including marketing statistics, and gemology periodicals. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Market surveys; Advertising -- History; Advertising, Outdoor; Jewelry -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Jewelry trade; Diamonds; Precious stones; N.W. Ayer & Son; Jeffery, Robert K.; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; De Beers Consolidated Mines
- Accession #2000-0328
  - Printed Materials (Box 1)
    - DeBeers Diamond Promotion Guide (Box 1)
    - DeBeers commissioned art (Box 1)
    - DeBeers Annual Reports, 1983-1987 (Box 1)
    - 50 Years of DeBeers Ads (Box 1)
    - DeBeers Ads - foreign (slides) (Box 1)
    - DeBeers Carat Club (Box 1)
    - DeBeers Promotional Materials (Box 1)
    - Ayer Glossary of Advertising and Related Terms, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Ayer: Information for employees (Box 1)
    - Gems and Gemology, 1990-1998 (Box 1)
    - Marketing workshop binder (Box 1)
    - The Market for Diamond Jewelry, United States, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Diamond Promotion Guide (Box 1)
    - Article on advertising from National Jeweler, 1986 June 1 (Box 1)
    - 1988 Red Book, The Market for Diamond Jewelry, United States (Box 1)
    - 1988 Blue Book, The Market for Diamond Jewelry, United States (Box 1)
    - Misc. diamond promotional materials (Box 1)
    - Robert K. Jeffery Resumé (Box 1)
  - Videotapes (Box 2)
    - 1. Rock video; 2. An International Affair, 2 spots, 1980s; 0:11:34 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-VHS-0006, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
    - The Diamond Promotion Service Audiovisual Training Program, "The Diamond Engagement Ring", 1987-03-13; 0:21:21 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-VHS-0001, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
    - Training programs with booklet
      - Diamonds for Men, 1987-03-11; 0:19:33 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-VHS-0009, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
      - Diamond Product Knowledge, 1988-04; 0:24:00 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-VHS-0008, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
    - NW Ayer, Field Force Conference Tape (Box 2)
    - Ayer Field Force Conference Tape Revised, 1990, 2 tapes (Box 2)
    - Diamond Rules, 1990s; 1:06:11 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-VHS-0005, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
    - From Rules to Riches, 1990s; 0:11:31 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-VHS-0004, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
    - Power of Love, 1990, 1990-10-04; 0:07:10 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-VHS-0007, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
    - DPS Videos, 2 tapes (Box 2)
    - Large Stone Ring, 1988-11-03; 0:00:34 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-VHS-0003, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
    - Diamond Masters Speeches (Box 2)
    - NW Ayer, Spring '89, 1989; 0:47:14 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-VHS-0002, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
    - Ayer 1990 Dealer Version, Commercial Reel (Box 2)
    - Adamas K - The Wizard of Opportunity (Box 2)
    - Beauty of Diamonds, 1991-09-29; 0:00:31 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL00633-UM-0001, Digital-materials RL00633-SET-0001)
  - Promotional Materials (matches, playing cards) (Box 2)
  - Album of DeBeers advertisments, 1939-1990s (Box 3)
  - Printed artwork and diamond promotional posters (Oversize-folder 1)